{"tossups": [{"question": "This government adopted a motto from the Warring States period, \u201cenrich the state, strengthen the military.\u201d This government abolished the han system, returning land to the central government, and abolished the existing class structure in the Charter Oath. This government\u2019s power was solidified after the Boshin War, in which samurai loyal to the Tokugawa Shogunate were defeated. For ten points, name this modernizing government that ruled Japan after the 1868 restoration of the emperor.", "answer": "<b> Meiji</b> government (accept<b> Meiji</b> Restoration, the government of Emperor<b> Meiji</b>, etc.)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This event was won five straight times by Taiwan before their defeat in 1980 by Kirkland, Washington. The 2014 runner-up in this event was the first all-black team to win the U.S. title, but was retroactively disqualified; that team, representing Jackie Robinson West in Chicago, was ruled to have violated this event\u2019s residency rules. In 2001, the Bronx team finished third in this event with Danny Almonte, who was later found to be 14 years old. For ten points, name this annual international baseball tournament held in South Williamsport, Pennsylvania for 11- to 13-year-olds.", "answer": "<b> Little League</b> Baseball<b> World Series</b> (or<b> LLWS</b>; do not accept or prompt on World Series alone)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Arthur Wellesley blamed the outcome of this battle on Alexander Cochrane. The losing side at this battle crucially forgot to bring ladders. Jean Lafitte [la-feet] aided the winners of this battle, in which Edward Pakenham was killed while only eight American soldiers died. This battle was fought shortly after the Treaty of Ghent was signed. For ten points, name this War of 1812 battle won by Andrew Jackson in Louisiana.", "answer": "Battle of<b> New Orleans</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This novel\u2019s protagonist pursues the affections of both Constance Bonacieux and Milady de Winter, who conspires to separate the Duke of Buckingham and Queen Anne with the help of Cardinal Richelieu. In this novel, the heartbroken Comte de la F`ere adopts the nickname Athos and fights alongside Porthos and Aramis before being joined by d\u2019Artagnan [dar-tan-YAN]. For ten points, name this novel by Alexandre Dumas about a small group of soldiers who live by the principle of \u201cone for all and all for one.\u201d", "answer": "The<b> Three Musketeers</b> (or Les<b> Trois Mousquetaires</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "After this city soundly defeated an opposing fleet at Curzola, the opposing admiral, Andrea Dandolo, committed suicide. This city\u2019s fleet was led by Luciano and Pietro Doria during the War of Chioggia, which it lost, marking the end of its rivalry with Venice. This Ligurian city\u2019s fleet was led at the Battle of Lepanto by Andrea Doria. For ten points, name this city on the northwest coast of Italy, the birthplace of explorer Christopher Columbus.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Genoa</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "William Seward gave the \u201cHigher Law\u201d speech to oppose this proposal, which was supported by the Georgia Platform. This proposal set the present borders of Texas and rejected a law governing the Utah and New Mexico territories, the Wilmot Proviso. Under this proposal, California was admitted as a free state, the slave trade was banned in the District of Columbia, and a stronger Fugitive Slave Law was enacted. For ten points, name this compromise that prolonged the Civil War for ten years.", "answer": "<b> Compromise of 1850</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this King of the Franks and first Holy Roman Emperor.", "answer": "<b> Charlemagne</b> (or<b> Karl der Grosse</b> or<b> Carolus Magnus</b> or<b> Charles the Great</b>) Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "On this island, the Hova were commoners forced into providing labor or a tax unless they paid a tax to a European colonist. This island was home to the Merina Kingdom until the French overthrew it in 1896; the French then established plantations worked by the native Malagasy people. For ten points, name this large island across the Mozambique Channel off the southeast coast of Africa, home to a modern country with capital Antananarivo.", "answer": "<b> Madagascar</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This city\u2019s \u201cYellow Car\u201d streetcars were taken over by the GM subsidiary National City Lines in 1945. In a series of \u201cWater Wars,\u201d Owens Valley farmers attempted to sabotage this city\u2019s namesake aqueduct, which was built by William Mulholland. A portion of Interstate 10 collapsed here in the 1994 Northridge earthquake, whose epicenter was in Reseda, a neighborhood in the San Fernando Valley. For ten points, name this city, the most populous in Southern California.", "answer": "<b> Los Angeles</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this Texan who became President after the death of John F. Kennedy.", "answer": "<b> L</b>yndon Baines<b> Johnson</b> (or<b> LBJ</b>, prompt on Johnson alone)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Two Partition Treaties were signed to prevent this war, while the Barrier Treaties allowed one of the victors to set up a series of forts as a buffer. The capture of Port Royal in Acadia occurred in its North American theater, which was called Queen Anne\u2019s War. Great Britain gained Gibraltar after this war, during which Marshal Tallard was crushed at the Battle of Blenheim [BLEN-um]. This war began after the death of the childless Charles II and the proposed accession of Phillip of Anjou. For ten points, name this war, ended by the Treaty of Utrecht, fought over the throne of the namesake Iberian nation.", "answer": "War of the<b> Spanish Succession</b> (accept<b> Queen Anne\u2019s</b> War before mention)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This nation endured a failed 1926 coup by General Emiliano Chamorro who, 12 years earlier, had signed a treaty with William Jennings Bryan. Adolfo D\u00b4\u0131az twice led this country, which was also ruled by the Somoza family and the (+) filibuster William Walker. In 1986, the International Court of Justice ruled that the U.S. violated international law by mining this country\u2019s harbors in support of a rebel group opposed to (*)</b> Daniel Ortega\u2019s Sandinistas. For ten points, name this Central American country where Ronald Reagan\u2019s administration secretly funded Contra rebels.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Nicaragua</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This tradition was criticized in an 1908 Arthur Lovejoy paper about \u201cThe Thirteen [of these],\u201d which accused it of defining \u201ctruth\u201d and \u201cbelief\u201d ambiguously. The \u201cneo\u201d form of this school was developed by a man who rejected the idea that philosophy should be a (+)\u201cmirror of nature,\u201d Richard Rorty. A developer of this school of thought wrote the tract\u201cHow To Make Our Ideas Clear\u201d about this movement and worked with (*)</b> William James on its development. For ten points, name this American philosophical tradition, founded by Charles Sanders Peirce and named for its focus on the practical effects of thought.", "answer": "<b> pragmatism</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b>Prior to this battle, the winning commander sent Sicinnus to the opposing camp to fake treason, drawing their forces into an arm of the Saronic Gulf. The losing commander at this battle lamented \u201cmy (+) men have turned into women, my women men,\u201d after he observed Artemisia of Halicarnassus ramming her own ally to escape. Athens was (*)</b> abandoned prior to this battle, which vindicated the \u201cwooden wall\u201d navy built by Themistocles. For ten points, name this 480 BC naval battle in which Xerxes\u2019 Persian navy was crushed by a Greek alliance.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Salamis</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The name of a river in this modern-day country now means \u201cdisaster\u201d in French after an 1812 victory for Peter Wittgenstein. A World War II battle fought in this country ended with the creation of the Navahrudak pocket. Napoleon\u2019s forces were harried across the Berezina River in this country. Negotiations held in this modern country gave the (+) Baltic States to Germany; Leon Trotsky agreed to those concessions in the Treaty of (*) </b>Brest-Litovsk. For ten points, name this country led by Alexander Lukashenko from its capital at Minsk.", "answer": "<b> Belarus</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This mathematician proved the undecidability of the halting problem. A finite set of user instructions, an infinitely long memory tape, and a symbol reader make up a theoretical</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>machine conceived by this man; if a problem is computable, that device can solve</b> <b>it, according to a hypothesis named for this man and Alonzo Church. A computer that is indistinguishable from a human in (*) </b> conversation would pass this man\u2019s namesake test. For ten points, name this British computer scientist who helped break the Enigma code during World War II before being prosecuted for his homosexuality.", "answer": "Alan<b> Turing</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Computer Science"}, {"question": "<b>The popular vote margin between this man and Winfield Scott Hancock was less than 2,000 votes. This politician was nominated for President on the 36th ballot after 35 ballots were split between former President (+) Grant and this man\u2019s choice for Secretary of State, James Blaine. This man\u2019s death at the hands of a (*)</b> Stalwart left him with the second-shortest Presidential term in history. For ten points, name this U.S. President who was assassinated in 1881 by Charles Guiteau and succeeded as President by Chester Arthur.", "answer": "James<b> Garfield</b>  (1) <b>Despite the protests of the DNC, Lyndon Johnson snubbed this politician in</b> <b>favor of Hubert Humphrey as his running mate. This politician rose to prominence</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>investigating mafia connections within worker unions, leading him into conflict</b> <b>investigating mafia connections within worker unions, leading him into conflict</b> <b>with the Teamsters and Jimmy Hoffa. Eugene McCarthy conceded (*)</b> <b>with the Teamsters and Jimmy Hoffa. Eugene McCarthy conceded (*)</b> California to this politician shortly before Sirhan Sirhan shot this man in 1968. For ten points, name this U.S. Attorney General and member of the Kennedy family. ANSWER:<b> R</b>obert Francis<b> Kennedy</b> (or<b> Bobby Kennedy</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}